# RYAN S.L. CARPENTER

## SOFTWARE ENGINEER & ENTREPRENEUR

+852 6462 6099 • ryan.sl.carpenter@gmail.com • Hong Kong • http://rslc.us

### SKILLS Full-Stack Web Development

I have built the complete tech stack of multiple corporate-ready web and hybrid mobile apps—both individually and by managing a developer team. I prefer an agile approach, allowing better product feedback from a fast release cycle. I am well-versed in multiple front-end and back-end JavaScript frameworks. As an entrepreneur, I've also managed our devops, including continuous integration tools and serverless architectures.

#### **Software Product Management**

I have steered several software products from concept, through development and testing to ongoing operations. I enjoy tackling a complex problem, imagining how a solution can be applied, then carefully managing the steps to build it effectively and efficiently.

#### **Team Leadership**

Although my career in small companies has meant managing smaller teams, I have worked hard to develop my skills as a team manager and have successfully remote-managed transnational, multilingual teams. In addition to organizing their development work, I mentored my team and ensured that their skill sets were consistently growing to support our future needs. I have also managed community groups, including organizing our local masters swimming team (100+ members).

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### Emotics • Co-founder & Tech Lead

MAR 2017 - PRESENT, HONG KONG

Founded Emotics to solve some clear failings in corporate learning software. Approached a solution from two directions: gathering real-time, subconscious feedback on the content that each learner is viewing and monitoring learning sessions to identify "cheating" behaviors. Led Emotics' tech development, building an SDK to integrate with client software, an API to collect data and serve results, and a front-end website for compliance managers to view analytics and review alerts. Maintained infrastructure, tests, and documentation for enterprise-level reliability and issue response. Supported investment and sales efforts by clearly explaining system architectures, managing on-boarding, and addressing IT concerns. Served several fortune 500 companies in the financial services and insurance sector.

#### **GBST** • App Strategy Consultant / Product Manager

JAN 2015 - APR 2016, HONG KONG

Formed a strategy for integrating mobile apps into GBST's financial services software. Hired and remotely-managed development team based in Vietnam. Built prototypes and pitched them to GBST clients, following agile processes for frequent releases.

#### **Exicon** • Director of Operations

APR 2014 - NOV 2014, HONG KONG

Identified gaps in and reorganized the company budget to successfully reduce costs and increase revenues. Created a pricing strategy to be attractive to both low-touch users and large enterprise clients. Established team metrics and the systems to monitor them.

#### LoadStar / Savi Networks • Program Manager

SEP 2007- MAR 2014. HONG KONG / CALIFORNIA

Directed hardware development of our shipping-container-monitoring product through a new Chinese manufacturing partner. Supported the management of our 30-person software development team contracted in Beijing.

 $\textbf{Lockheed Martin} \bullet \mathsf{TSAT}\,\mathsf{Mission}\,\mathsf{Operations}\,\mathsf{System}\,(\mathsf{TMOS})\,\mathsf{Risk}\,\mathsf{Manager}$ 

SEP 2004 - SEP 2007, SAN JOSE, CALIFORNIA

Managed authors of a 500+ page bid-winning, proposal document for a large defense contract. Directed the creation of mitigation plans that would eliminate 90% of program risk over contract lifetime and monitored their execution.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **Stanford University** • M.S. Aeronautics and Astronautics

2005 - 2007, PALO ALTO, CALIFORNIA

Through Stanford's Center for Professional Development, I completed their master's degree curriculum on evenings and weekends, while working full-time at Lockheed Martin.

#### Harvey Mudd College • B.S. Engineering

2000 - 2004, CLAREMONT, CALIFORNIA

HMC is a prestigious liberal arts college focused on engineering, math, and sciences. It is collocated with four other undergraduate schools, forming the Claremont Colleges.

#### pwc Scale Program • Startup Accelerator

2020, LONDON, UNITED KINGDOM (REMOTE)

#### **StartupBootCamp** • Startup Accelerator

2019, MELBOURNE, AUSTRALIA

**Lockheed Martin Engineering Dev. Program •** Corporate Leadership Program

2005-2008, SAN JOSE, CALIFORNIA

#### **INTERESTS**

I am a father to a precocious 4-year-old daughter and a husband to a talented, dedicated swimming director. I had a long career in swimming including leadership roles on both my college and adult (masters) teams. Living in Hong Kong has also introduced me to dragon boat racing and an a cappella singing group where I taught myself to arrange our own songs for four voices. I enjoy combining my web development skills with my interest in cartography to create unique, interactive maps, from Hong Kong public transit, to the voyages of Zheng He, to the world of Game of Thrones.

#### **AWARDS**

Emotics has been recognized by the government of Hong Kong, winning the HKICT Silver Award in 2018, and Regulation Asia. Emotics has also won acceptance into competitive business accelerators like Seedstars, Startupbootcamp, and pwc Scale.

At Lockheed Martin, I was one of 5% of new employees to participate in the Engineering Leadership Development Program.

I am proud to have helped my dragon boat team win the Stanley International Championships as well as earn medals and break records with my swimming teams at NCAA Division III Nationals and FINA World Masters Championships. At home, I have received an honorary mug as World's Okayest Dad.

# HR SEARCH TERM LIST

This resume has been optimized to be read by human beings, but I know it will be run through recruiting software as well. Some tech search terms relevant to me:

Node.js, React, AngularJS, Cordova, JavaScript, AWS, Elastic Beanstalk, RDS, Rekognition, CloudFront, Lambda, API, SDK, PostgreSQL, MySQL, CircleCI, GitHub Actions, kanban, agile